Robert S. Pierce

Atlanta, GA; 617.850.5973; pierce1673@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-pierce-5509204

Front End Developer

Digital marketing leader with over 13 years of interactive experience. Diverse background in software engineering, content management, design process, and project management. Proven ability to manage multiple engagements comprised of several integrated project tracks including email, social media, and web.

SPECIALITES

- Front-End Web Development
- Email Development
- Content creation and management
- Project management tools and methods
- Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) Subject Matter Expert
- Copy Creation/Editing
- Quality Assurance
- Digital Asset Management
- Client Liaison

WORK EXPERIENCE

blacQube, LLC - Atlanta, GA 10/2010 - 09/2019 Project Manager/Digital Producer/Content Specialist Responsibilities:

- Front-End website construction and content management via AEM of AMG4Web Platform (version 4.0) (<u>www.mercedes-amg.com</u>).
- Email development using HTML and CSS for the Mercedes-AMG Private Lounge online community, utilizing media queries to create dynamic and responsive emails, and conducting rendering tests across email clients and mobile devices.
- Management of digital representation of new product initiatives, specifically, vehicle launch campaign websites for Mercedes-AMG.
- Liaison for executive and content teams on the time tracking and deployment of all content.
- Resource assignment/allocation based on project needs.
- Creation of monthly web statistics reports using the Adobe Site Catalyst analytics tool. Accomplishments:
 - Managed full product development lifecycle for AMG 2.0 and 3.0.
 - Led internationalization efforts for Mercedes-AMG core web property.

The SuperGroup - Atlanta, GA 12/2008 - 9/2009 Project Manager

Responsibilities:

- Marketing email production for national promotional tours including ABC television show "Wipeout", Kraft Lunchables, and Post Honeycomb Cereal
- Management of digital projects and properties.
- Management of non-dedicated team of Design, Development, and QA resources on multiple projects of varying size and complexity for multiple clients.
- Calculation/management of resource utilization/productivity.
- Resource assignment/allocation based on client/project needs.
- Prioritization/scheduling of projects from multiple client-side contacts.

Accomplishments:

- Managed creation of print collateral of 6 separate Johnson and Johnson brands for annual national sales meeting.
- Managed creation, launch, and maintenance of Social Media campaigns for ING Group corporate sponsorships division for the New York City Marathon.
- · Managed ING's "Your Number" Facebook banner campaign.
- Provided technical support to 3 separate tour staffs for national promotional tours for Kraft Lunchables and Post Honeycomb Cereal.

Engauge Digital - Atlanta, GA (Formerly Spunlogic) 11/2006 - 7/2008 Project Manager/Digital Producer

Responsibilities:

- Management of email campaigns for InterContinental Hotels Group; Honey Baked Ham; and McKenna Long & Aldridge LLP.
- Management of digital projects and properties.
- Management of non-dedicated team of Information Architecture, Design, Development, QA, and User Experience resources on multiple projects for varying
- Resource assignment based on client needs.
- Prioritization/scheduling of projects from multiple client-side contacts.

Accomplishments:

- Delivered site redesign projects for Atlanta Development Authority, Georgia Gwinnett College, and Junior Achievement of Georgia on time and within budget.
- Executed rebranding efforts for the Cingular AdWorks system to AT&T AdWorks.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology - Atlanta, GA Coding Boot Camp Certificate, Full Stack Web Development 1/2020 Sorrell College of Business at Troy University - Troy, AL MBA Management, 6/1999 General Assembly - Atlanta, GA Certificate in Front-End Web Development, 5/2017 Emory University - Atlanta, GA Certificate in Graphic Design, 6/2010 Auburn University - Auburn, AL BS Health Services Administration, 12/1996

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript *iQuery* Node.js Express. js MySQL HTML/CSS Bootstrap **Bulma CSS Framework**

SOFTWARE EXPERTISE

Adobe Experience Manager WordPress Joomla! Drupal

Adobe Creative Cloud: Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Illustrator, InDesign

Microsoft Office: Excel/Powerpoint/Word/Outlook

OTHER SKILLS

TortoiseSVN

Basecamp Project Management Tools Akamai Luna Control Suite Lyris Email Labs Silverpop Engage marketing platform Bronto Email Marketing Platform Adobe SiteCatalyst analytics suite